<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cloudware</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Cloudware</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Recovering data in Linux ext4</title>
      <link>/posts/recovering-files-removed-with-rm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/recovering-files-removed-with-rm/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Have you ever removed a file with rm [FILENAME] or even worse rm -rf [DIR] only to find out that that you didn&amp;rsquo;t have a backup?. Well this happend to me with a project I hadn&amp;rsquo;t pushed to Github, and could not recover despite my best efforts, coloquially I know that the file wasn&amp;rsquo;t really deleted, it was just stored in unallocated spaces and the pointers from the filesystem datastructures where no longer pointing to it, so the file was recoverable but I didn&amp;rsquo;t know how to get it back.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Helm3-secrets on KMS</title>
      <link>/posts/helm3-secrets/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/helm3-secrets/</guid>
      <description>Setup / Prerequisites  A working Kubenetes (GKE) Helm3 KMS Permissions Sops (https://github.com/mozilla/sops/)  Let&amp;rsquo;s Do it! Key Generation First off you need to create a user in IAM with permissions (KMS Admin), and setup gcloud with this user After this, create a key ring and keys with the following comands:
gcloud kms keyrings create helm \  --location us-west1 gcloud kms keys create helm-secrets \  --location us-west1 \  --keyring helm \  --purpose &amp;#34;encryption&amp;#34; --rotation-period &amp;#34;90d&amp;#34; \  --next-rotation-time &amp;#34;2020-05-30T01:00:00&amp;#34; This will create a key ring named helm with a key called helm-secrets in us-west1 with a 90 day rotation period starting on May 30th 2020.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who am I?</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>#Who Am I?
I am a Chilean Software Engineer turned Devops Engineer, although I code by day I attempt to do security research by night in whatever peaks my interest, usually these days its forensics and android, but I am hoping to shift gears to Kubernetes Security sometime in the future. This blog serves as my attempt to document whatever the hell I&amp;rsquo;m up to.
I wrote my thesis on android reverse engineering when graduating from UTFSM in Chile, it was a fun experience that brought me closer to the security world, today I&amp;rsquo;m working as a Kubernetes Engieer and trying to absorb the knoweledge from that world and figure out some way to apply it to security.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reverse Engineering Android Applications and Threat Intelligence</title>
      <link>/projects/reverse-engineering-android-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/reverse-engineering-android-apps/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This was my graduate thesis, in which I reversed engineered and android APK application, to then use a metasploit payload to launch malware from the infected app and then proceeded to attempt anti virus evasion.
I go through the android permission model, applicaiton settings and how app signing works. An overview of ARM architecture, to move on to a list of tools I used to reverse engineer, including Metasploit and APKTool.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/projects/linux-memory-forensics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/linux-memory-forensics/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>